

#### Profile

I am a Fullstack Developer, mainly focused in Javascript. I have experiences working with banking, retail and transport industries.

I have worked with a lot of technologies and frameworks like Angular 2+, Vue.js, Node.js, Java and C#. I also have some experiences with cloud services like AWS (Lambdas and Step Functions) and MS Azure (APIs and Databases).

My experiences allowed me to also work with Relational Databases (Postgres and SQL Server) and a bit of NoSQL (MongoDB).

I am always willing to learn something new and always open to learn new technologies! I also like to work under Agile methods and Scrum/Kanban teams as well.

# Employment History

Backend Developer at X-Team, Santiago

June 2021 — March 2022

Backend Developer role for Rstudio, specializing in Node.js and Microservices with express.js.

Worked with Salesforce APIs, OAuth Integration, Clearbit, AWS Lambdas and Step Functions. Maintained and developed high standard libraries for Rstudio's Business Automation ecosystem.

#### Full-stack Developer at Amaris, Santiago

April 2019 — June 2021

Consultant role as a Full-stack developer in Angular 8+, Vue.js, Node.js and Typescript for different clients, including Banking and Transport Services (Consorcio Banking and Sodexo).

- Sodexo: Made in Angular 2+, we had to make a complete overhaul of the company's transport service Movilpass (www.movilpass.cl)
- Consorcio: Consorcio required to be made very quickly a Portability Banking service portal, which helps to get potential new clients to bring their previous banking products from other banks to Consorcio. Frontend was made in Vue.js and mounted in Modyo, which served to host the application very similar of how Sharepoint or Django does Has cloud integration with AWS Lambda and API Gateway. Creation of RESTful APIs made in NestJS, integrating different AWS lambda and legacy services. We used Redis for cache and CI/CD with Gitlab.
- Extras: Training coach specialist in front-end technologies (to deliver training courses and workshops) like HTML and Angular.

#### **Details**

Los Alerces 3225 Apt. 28 Santiago Chile

+56963449698

francisco.gonzalez.lorca@gmail.com

Date / Place of birth

1985-05-27

Santiago de Chile

Nationality

Chilean

#### Links

Github Portfolio

#### **Skills**

Git

Angular

CSS

HTML5

HTML

PHP

jQuery

MongoDB

MySQL

Node.js

React

HTML & CSS

SQL

C#

Programming

.NET

### Developer at Lagash, Santiago

November 2018 — February 2019

Full-stack developer for a car insurance company called Tanner, using NodeJS and ReactJS.

- We developed a car insurance backoffice web portal fully hosted in Microsoft Azure.
- Backend was made in Node with Restify, using Azure's cloud databases for storage.
- Frontend was made using React + Redux and Material UI for the components. We had to integrate our microservices made in Node with the frontend app.

## Frontend Developer at everis, Santiago

October 2017 — August 2018

Front-end developer in Angular 2+/NodeJS for BCI (Office Banking), as a part of their Migration and Digital Transformation process.

- We worked in a huge Agile project which involved around five agile squads all working on the same product. Dailies and meetings were big!
- My squad had two frontend devs, two backend devs completely dedicated to Spring Boot, one QA person and one Tech Lead to guide us. I was one of the frontend devs.
- We frontend devs had also to develop not only in Angular, but also in the app's BFF (Backend for Frontend) that was made in Node.js with Express. Our job was to call the microservices made in Spring Boot and process/format the data ready for the frontend to use it.
- Technologies used: Angular 2+ (native, Material) and NodeJS (with Express).

#### Developer at Defontana, Santiago

September 2015 — October 2017

- .NET and VB Developer in ERP Products, Continuous Integration, and Backend REST solutions for Defontana's Digital Transformation process.
- Technologies used: C#, VB.NET, WCF (microservices), MS Web API, ASP.NET, Razor, SQL Server 2018
- Legacy technologies: VB 6, ASP

### Backend Developer at TUTEN, Santiago

April 2015 — August 2015

Backend designer, REST services programmer, Database developer.

Java
JavaScript
Docker
TypeScript
Angular 2+
NodeJS
Agile
Scrum
<b>Languages</b> Spanish
English

#### **Hobbies**

Open Source software contributor, Video Game developer in Unreal Engine

- TUTEN is a web/mobile app service that helps people search for professional household services (painting, plumbers, electrical, etc). Works similar to Uber.
- I designed the database and REST services for TUTEN app's first version.
- With the team, we travelled to Boston, USA for 3 months to MassChallenge's 2015 startup accelerator conference, to learn how to boost the startup business process and development cycle.
- Technologies used: Java, JAX-RS, Postgres SQL

#### Developer at TAISA Chile, Santiago

January 2011 — March 2015

Software Developer for web and mobile solutions, using .NET (C#, ASP.NET), Java (EE and WebSphere), SQL Server, PHP, plus maintaining some other legacy software used in Banking like ASP. Clients worked with: Santander, SURA, Corpbanca.

- Technologies used: C#, Java, ASP.NET, ASP, SQL Server.

# Education

## Computer Sciences, DUOC UC, Santiago

2005 - 2010

Focusing in Microsoft Technologies, and volunteer work in the Microsoft Student Partners program, educational talks in technology to local college.